North East Map Organization (NEMO) Records 2000.0044
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
North East Map Organization (NEMO) Records
undated, 1985-2003
2000.0044
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
1.25 Linear feet
The purpose of the North East Map Organization (NEMO) is to serve as a unifying body for all who use maps and cartographic information in the Northeast; increase communication between all parties interested in maps; and work with state, regional and national associations and government agencies in the dissemination of maps and cartographic information. The states that comprise the region of interest to NEMO include: Connecticut, Delaware, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island and Vermont.
North East Map Organization (NEMO).
History
The purpose of the North East Map Organization ( NEMO) is to serve as a unifying body for all who use maps and cartographic information in the Northeast; increase communication between all parties interested in maps; and work with state, regional and national associations and government agencies in the dissemination of maps and cartographic information. The states that comprise the region of interest to NEMO include: Connecticut, Delaware, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island and Vermont.
The first meeting of the organization was held on 7 October 1987 on the Storrs Campus of the University of Connecticut in conjunction with the Northeast NCIC State Affiliates' Fall Meeting.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence, membership lists, programs and the organization's newsletter (incomplete).
Arrangement
Series I: Records ( undated, 1985-2003 ) includes the official records of the organization arranged alphabetically by subject or document type.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Hagstrom Map & Travel Newsletter (6-8) Dodd Periodicals
NEMO Newsletter (1-28, 30-51, 53) Dodd Periodicals
Photographs (1996, 27 color snapshots) and slides (undated, 3) have been removed and housed appropriately.
Acquisition Information
The materials were donated by Patrick McGlamery in 2000. Subsequent additions have been donated by organization officers.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to a variety of Connecticut-based organizations. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
North East Map Organization (NEMO).; Administrative records; Cartographers; Cartography; Connecticut; Correspondence; Delaware; Map collections; New England; New Jersey; New York (State); Pennsylvania; Professional associations; Publications; Societies
- Series I: Records, undated, 1985-2003
  - Annual Meeting-- Storrs, Connecticut, 1987 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Annual Meeting-- Boston, Massachusetts, 1988 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Annual Meeting-- New London, New Hampshire, 1989 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Annual Meeting-- New Britain, Connecticut, 1990 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Annual Meeting-- Amherst, Massachusetts, 1991 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Annual Meeting-- New Brunswick, New Jersey, 1992 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Annual Meeting-- Buffalo, NY, [1993] (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Annual Meeting-- Boston, Massachusetts, 1994 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Annual Meeting-- Boston, Massachusetts, 1995 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Annual Meeting-- Woods Hole, Massachusetts, 1996 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Annual Meeting-- Swarthmore, Pennsylvania, 1997 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Annual Meeting-- North Dartmouth, Massachusetts, 1998 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Annual Meeting-- Wellesley, Massachusetts, 1999 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Annual Meeting-- Portland, Maine, 2000 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Annual Meeting-- South Hadley, Massachusetts, 2001 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Annual Meeting-- Boston, Massachusetts, 2003 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - Annual Meeting--Locations, 1987-2001 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - Articles, 1985, 1991 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Cartomania, undated (Box 2:, Folder 19)
  - Conference Notes, undated (Box 2:, Folder 20)
  - Congress of Cartographic Information Specialist Associations, undated, 1988-1990 (Box 2:, Folder 21)
  - Connecticut Atlas, undated (Box 2:, Folder 22)
  - Constitution and By-laws, undated (Box 2:, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1989-1996 (Box 2:, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence--De Blij, 1999 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
  - Financial materials, undated (Box 2:, Folder 26)
  - Ground Zero maps, 2001 December, 2002 March (Box 2:, Folder 27)
  - Lomba, Dan talk, 1998 June 21 (Box 2:, Folder 28)
  - Map Project, 1999 (Box 2:, Folder 29)
  - Membership, 1991-1993, 1997-1998 (Box 2:, Folder 30)
  - Newsletter Editor, undated, 1992-1996 (Box 2:, Folder 31)
  - Notes, undated (Box 2:, Folder 32)
  - Paige Gibbs file, 2001-2003 (Box 3:, Folder 36)
  - Planning Committee, 1989, 1992 (Box 2:, Folder 33)
  - Publications, undated, 1990-1996 (Box 2:, Folder 34)
  - Publications --The Five Colleges, undated (Box 3:, Folder 35)
  - Washington Map Society, 1990 (Box 3:, Folder 36)